<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux-konsult.com</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/</link><description>Recent content on linux-konsult.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 14:30:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://linux-konsult.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Let karpenters just-in-time scheduler manage disk pressure</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/k8s/karpenter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/k8s/karpenter/</guid><description>Overview It can be challenging to do capacity planning in kubernetes. Karpenter can be used for automatic rightscaling (and rightsizing) of kubernetes nodes in an EKS cluster, but it usually only handle CPU and memory. We had an issue where GitLab CI jobs quickly filled up node storage. The node disk usage was big enough to almost fill the disk to 98-99%. The CI job itself did not fail, but parallell jobs sheduled on the same node sometimes would.</description></item><item><title>Solar energy prices and storage</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/energy/pv-prices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 09:50:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/energy/pv-prices/</guid><description>Trust is breaking down between european countries. We may have the first european war winter in a scale not seen since the second world war&amp;hellip;
As a result, we&amp;rsquo;ve seen a steep increase of energy prices, and we may not have seen the worst so far. Another &amp;ldquo;solution&amp;rdquo; mentioned by our great leaders are to instigate price controls, and we all know what that means: power outages when the demand is not allowed to be regulated by pricing!</description></item><item><title>Install ArgoCD</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/k8s/argocd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/k8s/argocd/</guid><description>Quick install mkdir -p ~/git/github.com/argoproj cd ~/git/github.com/argoproj kubectl create namespace argocd git clone https://github.com/argoproj/argo-cd.git kubectl apply --namespace argocd -f ~/git/github.com/argoproj/argo-cd/manifests/install.yaml Access ArgoCD To access ArgoCD you port forward as below. The installation process automatically creates an admin user. You&amp;rsquo;ll see the generated password below.
echo &amp;#34;argocd password: $(kubectl -n argocd get secret argocd-initial-admin-secret -ojson | jq -r .data.password| base64 -d)&amp;#34; kubectl port-forward svc/argocd-server -n argocd 8080:443</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes with k3s on Raspberry Pi 4</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/k8s/rpi4-k3s/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/k8s/rpi4-k3s/</guid><description>Disk intensive applications such as kubernetes can run on Raspberry Pi 4, but you need to migrate from the SD card to an SSD drive. Trust me, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to run this from your SD card. I tried&amp;hellip;
Warning: I have noted down the steps taken, there may be some additional steps you need to take to get everything working. If so let me now through GitHub
Preparations K3S networking does not work with nftables, so switch to legacy iptables:</description></item><item><title>Migrate Raspberry Pi SD card to SSD</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/rpi/rpi4-ssd/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 09:00:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/rpi/rpi4-ssd/</guid><description>Disk intensive applications such as kubernetes can run on Raspberry Pi 4, but you need to migrate from the SD card to an SSD drive.
Raspberry Pi can boot from USB, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to wear out your SD card anymore.
This is what you need to configure your raspberry pi:
A USB3 SATA or M.2 case SSD disk Os already installed on the old SD card Set up Boot up your rpi4 on the SD card.</description></item><item><title>Prometheus monitoring of BME280 sensor readings</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/observability/prom-bme280/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 19:07:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/observability/prom-bme280/</guid><description>I wanted to be able to monitor the environment in my RV, so this weekend I created the esp32_prometheus_exporter_BME280.
My plan later is to monitor it and send alerts with LoraWan so I know my cat is OK I want to leave it in the vehicle. With LoraWan I should be able to get notified without cellular coverage.
For now it&amp;rsquo;s just a regular wifi based sensor since I don&amp;rsquo;t have the lora hardware yet.</description></item><item><title>Airgap your Raspberry Pi on a shoestring budget</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/airgapping-rpi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 22:16:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/airgapping-rpi/</guid><description>Airgapping is a method used when you want to be reasonable sure your device wasn&amp;rsquo;t tampered with. Regardless if you want to install a Seedsigner or something else. The best is to never have had it connected to your network in the first place.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how I used a $1 USB serial programmer for an ESP-01 to configure an off-line Raspberry Pi. I&amp;rsquo;ll also show how to transfer files to your machine with this oldschool method.</description></item><item><title>Links collection</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 15:28:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/links/</guid><description>What Is Platform Engineering? Gartners overview on Platform Engineering
Why putting a pane of glass on a pile of sh*t doesn’t solve your problem Sometimes better observability will just help you see problems you know are already there.
Architecting Internal Developer Platforms: Humanitec and Crossplane Learn how you can build an Internal Developer Platform using Crossplane, Humanitec and GitHub Actions</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Mining</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/bitcoin/btc-miners/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 18:07:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/bitcoin/btc-miners/</guid><description>As trust is currently breaking down between countries, some miners experience incredible pain at the moment. Many who has been hosting their miners in Russia may loose their hardware I expect!
As a result, there may be difficulties finding hosting in the United States as miners scramble to get their hardware to safer havens. Not your keys, not your bitcoin as you say, may now need to be extended to Not your facility, not your miner.</description></item><item><title>Monitor your freezer with Prometheus and Grafana</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/projects/projects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/projects/projects/</guid><description>Prometheus monitored freezer Monitor a freezer with Prometheus and Grafana As a preparation of increased food prices, freezed food will be a more and more important asset to monitor. I use a cheap ESP8266 NodeMCU unit with a Dallas DS18B20 temperature sensor to monitor the freezer.
It uses PlatformIO to become a WiFi enabled device that is scraped by Prometheus and visualized in Grafana. Prometheus alarms can then monitor and page you if the freezer loose it&amp;rsquo;s temperature.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/about/</guid><description>I work as a Tech Lead in a newly formed SRE team for a cloud based backend for autonomous semitrucks. With a previous focus strongly in favor of AWS cloud services, We now focus on transitioning to a Cloud Native observability stack.
In order to always learn new things I try to stay junior and humble.
Work Site Reliability Engineer - Tech lead, transition observability to a cloud native stack</description></item></channel></rss>