<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux-konsult.com</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/</link><description>Recent content on linux-konsult.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 19:07:07 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://linux-konsult.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prometheus monitoring of BME280 sensor readings</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/observability/prom-bme280/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 19:07:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/observability/prom-bme280/</guid><description>I wanted to be able to monitor the environment in my RV, so this weekend I created the esp32_prometheus_exporter_BME280.
My plan later is to monitor it and send alerts with LoraWan so I know my cat is OK I want to leave it in the vehicle. With LoraWan I should be able to get notified without cellular coverage.
For now it&amp;rsquo;s just a regular wifi based sensor since I don&amp;rsquo;t have the lora hardware yet.</description></item><item><title>Airgap your Raspberry Pi on a shoestring budget</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/airgapping-rpi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 22:16:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/airgapping-rpi/</guid><description>Airgapping is a method used when you want to be reasonable sure your device wasn&amp;rsquo;t tampered with. Regardless if you want to install a Seedsigner or something else. The best is to never have had it connected to your network in the first place.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how I used a $1 USB serial programmer for an ESP-01 to configure an off-line Raspberry Pi. I&amp;rsquo;ll also show how to transfer files to your machine with this oldschool method.</description></item><item><title>Observability</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 15:28:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/links/</guid><description>Why putting a pane of glass on a pile of sh*t doesn’t solve your problem
Interesting take on why better observability isn&amp;rsquo;t always the right thing to pursue if you already know ther is a problem - you&amp;rsquo;ll just see problems you know are already there.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Mining</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/bitcoin/btc-miners/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 18:07:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/bitcoin/btc-miners/</guid><description>As trust is currently breaking down between countries, some miners experience incredible pain at the moment. Many who has been hosting their miners in Russia may loose their hardware I expect!
As a result, there may be difficulties finding hosting in the United States as miners scramble to get their hardware to safer havens. Not your keys, not your bitcoin as you say, may now need to be extended to Not your facility, not your miner.</description></item><item><title>Monitor your freezer with Prometheus and Grafana</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/projects/projects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/projects/projects/</guid><description>Prometheus monitored freezer Monitor a freezer with Prometheus and Grafana As a preparation of increased food prices, freezed food will be a more and more important asset to monitor. I use a cheap ESP8266 NodeMCU unit with a Dallas DS18B20 temperature sensor to monitor the freezer.
It uses PlatformIO to become a WiFi enabled device that is scraped by Prometheus and visualized in Grafana. Prometheus alarms can then monitor and page you if the freezer loose it&amp;rsquo;s temperature.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/about/</guid><description>I work as a Tech Lead in a newly formed SRE team for a cloud based backend for autonomous semitrucks. With a previous focus strongly in favor of AWS cloud services, We now focus on transitioning to a Cloud Native observability stack.
In order to always learn new things I try to stay junior and humble.
Work Site Reliability Engineer - Tech lead, transition observability to a cloud native stack</description></item></channel></rss>