<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Karpenter on linux-konsult.com</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/tags/karpenter/</link><description>Recent content in Karpenter on linux-konsult.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 13:50:07 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://linux-konsult.com/tags/karpenter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Energy, prosperity and mindset of sustainability in the cloud</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/energy/cloud_energy_sustainability/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 13:50:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/energy/cloud_energy_sustainability/</guid><description>&lt;p>Energy is a key factor for human prosperity. It is essential for providing the power needed for transportation, heating and cooling, lighting, and other daily activities. It also plays a crucial role in supporting economic growth and development, as it is needed to run factories, power plants, other infrastructure, and services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://linux-konsult.com/img/europe-grid.png" alt="Europe">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a wealth of data that supports the importance of energy for human prosperity. For example, the World Bank reports that access to modern energy services is a key factor in reducing poverty and promoting economic growth. The International Energy Agency (IEA) also finds that improving access to modern energy can have a major impact on health, education, and other indicators of human development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Let karpenters just-in-time scheduler manage disk pressure</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/k8s/karpenter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/k8s/karpenter/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">
 Overview
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#overview">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Capacity planning in Kubernetes can be challenging.
Karpenter is useful for automatically rightscaling and rightsizing Kubernetes nodes in an EKS cluster, but it usually only considers CPU and memory usage. We experienced difficulties troubleshooting this issue because the node storage was not full at the time we checked it. The disk usage would spike to almost capacity (98-99%) during the execution of GitLab CI jobs, then decrease after the job was completed. This made it difficult to identify the cause of the issue.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>