<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on linux-konsult.com</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on linux-konsult.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 09:00:11 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://linux-konsult.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Airgap your Raspberry Pi on a shoestring budget</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/rpi/rpi4-ssd/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 09:00:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/rpi/rpi4-ssd/</guid><description>To run for example k3s, kubernetes or other more disk intensive applications on your Raspberry Pi 4 I needed to migrate from the internal SD card to an external USB3 SSD drive. Raspberry Pi can boot from USB, and this is how it&amp;rsquo;s done.
This is what you need to configure your raspberry pi:
A USB3 SATA or M.2 case SSD disk Os already installed on the old SD card Set up Boot up your rpi4 on the SD card.</description></item><item><title>Prometheus monitoring of BME280 sensor readings</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/observability/prom-bme280/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 19:07:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/observability/prom-bme280/</guid><description>I wanted to be able to monitor the environment in my RV, so this weekend I created the esp32_prometheus_exporter_BME280.
My plan later is to monitor it and send alerts with LoraWan so I know my cat is OK I want to leave it in the vehicle. With LoraWan I should be able to get notified without cellular coverage.
For now it&amp;rsquo;s just a regular wifi based sensor since I don&amp;rsquo;t have the lora hardware yet.</description></item><item><title>Airgap your Raspberry Pi on a shoestring budget</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/airgapping-rpi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 22:16:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/airgapping-rpi/</guid><description>Airgapping is a method used when you want to be reasonable sure your device wasn&amp;rsquo;t tampered with. Regardless if you want to install a Seedsigner or something else. The best is to never have had it connected to your network in the first place.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how I used a $1 USB serial programmer for an ESP-01 to configure an off-line Raspberry Pi. I&amp;rsquo;ll also show how to transfer files to your machine with this oldschool method.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Mining</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/bitcoin/btc-miners/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 18:07:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/bitcoin/btc-miners/</guid><description>As trust is currently breaking down between countries, some miners experience incredible pain at the moment. Many who has been hosting their miners in Russia may loose their hardware I expect!
As a result, there may be difficulties finding hosting in the United States as miners scramble to get their hardware to safer havens. Not your keys, not your bitcoin as you say, may now need to be extended to Not your facility, not your miner.</description></item></channel></rss>