<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>k8s on linux-konsult.com</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/tags/k8s/</link><description>Recent content in k8s on linux-konsult.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 22:00:07 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://linux-konsult.com/tags/k8s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fluent Bit: Isolating pod logs in a multitenant EKS cluster</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/observability/fluent-bit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 22:00:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/observability/fluent-bit/</guid><description>Overview In this post, we discuss how to isolate log access in a multitenant AWS EKS cluster between tenants. This solution is intended for those who need to give customer team members access to their own microservice log output without replicating the log storage out to other logging solutions or out of the AWS account to minimize the risk of data leakage.
Situation We have a multi-tenant EKS Kubernetes cluster that is used as an internal development platform.</description></item><item><title>When to extend a helm chart and when to use a subchart</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/k8s/helm_subcharts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 09:36:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/k8s/helm_subcharts/</guid><description>Overview A Helm chart is a package of Kubernetes resources that can be managed and deployed as a unit. It is defined using YAML files and follows a specific directory structure, with a Chart.yaml file that contains metadata about the chart, and one or more templates that define the resources to be deployed. Helm charts can be used to deploy applications, services, or infrastructure on Kubernetes clusters.
A Helm subchart is a reusable, modular component of a Helm chart that can be defined and managed independently.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes with k3s on Raspberry Pi 4</title><link>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/k8s/rpi4-k3s/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://linux-konsult.com/posts/k8s/rpi4-k3s/</guid><description>Disk intensive applications such as kubernetes can run on Raspberry Pi 4, but you need to migrate from the SD card to an SSD drive. Trust me, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to run this from your SD card. I tried&amp;hellip;
Warning: I have noted down the steps taken, there may be some additional steps you need to take to get everything working. If so let me now through GitHub
Preparations K3S networking does not work with nftables, so switch to legacy iptables:</description></item></channel></rss>